bcferries.com 2018-12-22

# British Columbia Ferry Services Inc. | BC Ferries - British Columbia Ferry Services Inc.

## Website Privacy Statement

British Columbia Ferry Services Inc. (BC Ferries) is committed to protecting your privacy through responsible personal information management practices in accordance with British Columbia’s _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_ and other applicable laws, such as the _Coastal Ferry Act_ and Canada’s Anti-Spam Legislation.

**Personal information**

> Personal information is recorded information about an identifiable individual, e.g.,
> 
>   * Name
>   * Address
>   * Birth date
>   * Personal email address 
>   * Personal telephone number
> 

> 
> Personal information does not include certain types of **contact** information which enable individuals at a place of business to be contacted, e.g.,
> 
>   * Individual’s business position, title or name
>   * Business telephone number
>   * Business address
>   * Business email 
>   * Business fax number
> 

**  
 Visiting our website **

> When you visit the BC Ferries website, our web server automatically collects the following information:
> 
>   * Internet Protocol address of your device
>   * Domain name
>   * Type of device
>   * Operating system
>   * Browser type
>   * Pages viewed and content downloaded
> 

> 
> This information is only collected to monitor use and to help improve our website, and to provide you with the best possible web experience. 

**  
Collection, use & disclosure of personal information**

> When you contact BC Ferries, you may be asked to voluntarily provide personal information, such as your:
> 
>   * Personal name
>   * Personal contact information, including email, mailing address, telephone number and fax number
>   * Login and password information
>   * Credit card information
>   * Travel reservation, booking and other transaction details
>   * And other details related to the subject matter you are communicating with us about
> 

> 
> BC Ferries collects your personal information in accordance with the _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_. We may collect your personal information to:
> 
>   * Administer your account, or process your reservations and other transactions with us
>   * Process payments with our payment services provider(s)
>   * Confirm your identity
>   * Facilitate your travel and your BC Ferries Vacations arrangements
>   * Comply with Transport Canada regulations or other statutory, legal or regulatory requirements
>   * Contact and correspond with you, including sending you notifications and information you have requested, or communicating with you about commercial or administrative matters.  In addition, only if you opt to receive such communications, we will send you promotional information and other notices about our services and offers which we or our computer systems have identified as potentially of interest to you based on your purchasing history and preferences.
> 

> 
> We may also collect personal information to improve our website services, to administer our website, and to protect the security of the website when necessary.  You can choose not to provide certain requested personal information, but then you may not be able to use certain services provided by BC Ferries or access or use certain features of our website.
> 
> Personal information is normally collected directly from you but may also be received from a third party, such as a travel agent acting on your authority or from a credit card service provider if the information is for the purpose of making an online payment to BC Ferries. 
> 
> Your personal information will be used and disclosed only as authorized or required by the _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_ or other applicable law _._ We may share your personal information, for instance, with our employees or our service providers who need it to perform their duties, and with others in specific circumstances, such as payment processors, law enforcement, emergency contacts, or in civil proceedings.  BC Ferries does not sell or rent personal information to third parties, and must also adhere to laws which place limits on access to or disclosure of your personal information outside Canada.
> 
> Unless we have your consent, we will only use your information for the purpose it was obtained or compiled, or for a use consistent with that purpose.
> 
> If you have any questions about the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information, please contact us. 

**  
Digital markers (including Cookies)**

> A digital marker is created by a website visitor’s Internet browser to maintain certain pieces of information for the website to reference during the same or subsequent visits. Examples of digital markers are Cookies or HTML5 Web storage. Among other things, digital markers can allow a website to recognize a previous visit each time the visitor accesses the website, and track what information is viewed on a website.
> 
> BC Ferries uses sessional and persistent digital markers on some portions of www.bcferries.com. Digital markers are created when you visit our website. Sessional markers exist while you remain on our website, and persistent markers continue to exist after you have left our website.
> 
> During your visit, your Internet browser exchanges data with BC Ferries’ web server. However, the digital markers used by us do not allow us to identify individuals unless a visitor specifically informs us of their identity, e.g., booking online or sending us correspondence through the website.
> 
> We may use the website information generated through the use of digital markers, and share it with other organizations with which we have a commercial relationship, to measure the use and to improve the functionality and content of our website.
> 
> You may adjust your browser settings to reject digital markers, including Cookies. However, if you refuse to accept Cookies, you may not be able to use some of the features available on our website.

**  
Web analytics**

> BC Ferries utilizes web analytics tools, including Google Analytics, to gain insights into how its website is used with a view to measuring business performance and improving customers’ online experience. Web analytics tags are applied to BC Ferries’ web pages to capture a limited amount of data which are used for aggregate reporting purposes.
> 
> The information captured by web analytics tools, including Google Analytics, includes:
> 
>   * Internet protocol address of the computer, device or network being used
>   * Domain name
>   * Type of computer or device
>   * Operating system
>   * Browser type
>   * Origin of a referral to BC Ferries’ website (called a traffic source; e.g., Google.com) 
>   * Users and number of sessions (called unique visitors and volume of visits)
>   * City/region/country of origin
>   * Pages viewed
>   * Session flow
>   * Products purchased
>   * Revenue generated
>   * Content downloaded
> 

> 
> None of the information collected is personally identifiable by BC Ferries or Google Analytics; however, this information could be processed outside Canada in any country where Google operates servers.
> 
> Analytics tools work by using Cookies. You may adjust your browser settings to reject digital markers, including Cookies. However, if you refuse to accept Cookies, you may not be able to use some of the features available on our website.

**  
Marketing and communications**

> BC Ferries will add you to our electronic subscription lists only if you provide your consent. If you choose to receive information about special offers and promotions, news releases or other electronic communications from BC Ferries, we will provide our contact information and a method to opt out of receiving further communications from us with each email or other electronic communication we send you.
> 
> BC Ferries collects information about recipients of the onBoard newsletter, including on-page user interaction, also known as **click and read** **activity**. This information is used to understand customer interest in the newsletter, including particular promotions, news and contests. BC Ferries will use this information to tailor its communications with individual customers only if they have first consented. 

**  
Contests and surveys**

> BC Ferries may run contests or conduct online surveys. Your participation in contests or surveys is entirely voluntary. Contest or survey information, such as age or other restrictions, can be found along with the specific contest or survey details.

**  
Your information rights**

> **Access and correction** :  You may request access to your personal information and/or correction of that information by contacting us at the address noted below or visit our Freedom of Information landing page for more details. If you seek records containing your personal information in electronic form, we will provide copies of the records in that form with our response, where it is reasonable to do so.
> 
> **Processing** :  You may request details about how we process your personal information. Subject to legal, regulatory or other requirements or circumstances, we will tell you:
> 
>   * Whether your personal information is being collected, used or disclosed, the categories of personal information, and the purposes for so doing; and
>   * Recipients or categories of recipients to whom your personal information has been disclosed.
> 

> 
> **Consent** :  Where you have given BC Ferries your written consent to use or disclose your personal information for a specific purpose, you may at any time contact us to withdraw your consent on a go-forward basis, unless your consent was given as part of a contractual agreement.  If you choose to withdraw your consent, you understand you may not be able to use or receive certain services provided by BC Ferries that related to that consent.
> 
> **Accuracy** :  You can help BC Ferries maintain the accuracy of your information by notifying us of any changes to your personal information.  When you contact us, we may ask for further details to confirm your identity. If you have a MyBCFerries account, you can update your details when you sign in. 

**  
Retention and storage of personal information**

> BC Ferries will securely retain and dispose of personal information in accordance with its records retention schedules. The period of the retention of your personal information will vary depending on why it was collected, and will be based on business, administrative, legal, financial or other factors. BC Ferries retains your personal information for at least 1 year if it has been used to make a decision affecting you. Unless authorized by the _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_ or other applicable law, we store all personal information in Canada.

**  
Security**

> BC Ferries takes reasonable steps to protect your personal information. We use technological, physical and managerial procedures intended to prevent the unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification of personal information submitted to this website. Our security practices are continually evolving to ensure that the integrity and confidentiality of information and systems are maintained.
> 
> Although we have security measures in place, you should be aware there is an element of risk whenever you send or receive information using the Internet. You should always carefully consider what information you choose to share. It is also your responsibility to safeguard your user identifications, passwords or any other special identifiers used to access our website.

**  
Links to other websites**

> BC Ferries’ website includes links to other websites. When you click on one of those links you are contacting another website. BC Ferries’ privacy statement does not apply to these other websites. BC Ferries has no responsibility or liability for or control over those other websites or their collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. If you access another organization's website through our website, you should read that organization's privacy policy to determine its website practices.

**  
Oversight**

> We encourage you to contact us at the address below if you have any questions or concerns about how we administer your personal information.
> 
> BC Ferries’ privacy practices are subject to independent oversight by British Columbia’s Information and Privacy Commissioner.  View the [Commissioner’s website](https://www.oipc.bc.ca/).

**  
Updates**

> BC Ferries will, as appropriate, review and update this privacy statement to ensure it is consistent with current privacy management and website administration practices.

* * *

**Contact us**

> For general questions about how we administer your personal information, please call or email our customer service team at:  
>  1-888-BC FERRY (1-888-223-3779)   
> 
> To exercise your information rights, please visit our FOI page or call, email or write to our FOIPP Office Manager at:  
>  250-978-1502   
> 
> Manager, FOIPP Office  
>  BC Ferries Head Office  
>  Suite 500, 1321 Blanshard Street  
>  Victoria, BC V8W 0B7
